The world has enough Superheroes.
Venom is a science fiction, action film directed by Ruben Fleischer.
Investigative journalist Eddie Brock attempts a comeback following a scandal, but
accidentally becomes the host of Venom, a violent, super powerful alien symbiote.
Soon, he must rely on his newfound powers to protect the world from a
shadowy organization looking for a symbiote of their own.
Eddie Brock / Venom, played by Tom Hardy.
Anne Weying, played by Michelle Williams.
Carlton Drake / Riot, played by Riz Ahmed.
Security Chief Roland Treece, played by Scott Haze.
Dr. Dan Lewis, played by Reid Scott.
Dr. Dora Skirth, played by Jenny Slate.
Venom is a 2018 American superhero film based on
the character from Marvel Comics.
The first film in Sony's Spider-Man Universe (SSU), it was directed by Ruben Fleischer
from a screenplay by Jeff Pinkner, Scott Rosenberg, and Kelly Marcel.
Tom Hardy stars as Eddie Brock and Venom, alongside Michelle
Williams, Riz Ahmed, Scott Haze, and Reid Scott.
In the film, Eddie, a struggling journalist, gains superpowers after becoming the
host of Venom, an alien symbiote whose species plans to invade Earth.
Following Venom's appearance in Spider-Man 3 (2007), Sony Pictures attempted to develop a spin-off film based on the
Venom character, which was stalled due to issues with the company's ongoing Spider-Man franchise.
In March 2016, work began on a new version that would start a new shared universe featuring
the non-Spider-Man Marvel characters that the studio possessed film rights to.
Sony also originally intended for the Venom film to share the world of the Marvel Cinematic Universe
film Spider-Man: Homecoming (2017), but ultimately distanced the film from Spider-Man.
Sony's Columbia Pictures produced the film in
association with Marvel Entertainment.
In March 2017, Rosenberg and Pinkner were set to write, with Fleischer and Hardy
added in May; Marcel subsequently joined to rewrite the script.
Filming took place from October 2017 to January 2018 in
Atlanta, New York City, and San Francisco.
The film was primarily inspired by the comic book miniseries Venom: Lethal
Protector (1993) and the story arc "Planet of the Symbiotes" (1995).
Ludwig Göransson was hired to compose the film's score, marking
his second Marvel film after Black Panther (2018).
Venom premiered at the Regency Village Theater on October 1, 2018,
and was released in the United States on October 5.
Despite generally negative reviews from critics, Hardy's performance and his character's relationship with Venom were praised, and the film became the
seventh-highest-grossing film of 2018, earning $856.1 million worldwide and setting several box office records for an October release.
Two sequels have been released: Venom: Let There Be Carnage
(2021) and Venom: The Last Dance (2024).
The film explores themes of spacecraft, san francisco,
california, superhero, anti hero, alien life-form.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.